Bawantha Rajapaksha Software Engineer

➤ bawwa.16@cse.mrt.ac.lk

+94771641667

• 42,Pohonnaruwa,Mirigama,Sri Lanka

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/bawantha-rajapaksha/

https://github.com/bawantha/

À https://stackoverflow.com/users/8135721/bawantha

Profile

Software Enginner at Codegen UK, 4 years experience mobile application developer. The mobile development stack is the core strength. Interested in devising a better problem solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Professional Experience

03/2021 –	present
lik	

Software Engineer, *Codegen International* □

- Contributed to the development of a mobile app for iOS and Android using Flutter and Ionic
- Create and maintaining full mobile app cycle for android and iOS with CI/CD pipelines using Fastlane + Gitlab
- Monolith to SaaS (Software as a Service) migration of Codegen's booking queue service used tech: Java,maven, tomcat, k8s
- Angular front-end development

03/2023 – present USA

03/1

08/2022 Australia

Mobile app developer (part-time), Al summon ☑

• Google map integration with custom markers

Mobile app developer (part-time), Blocktherapy Bliss ☑

- Optimized Firebase firestore backed for better query performance
- Implment secure video streaming module for user content.

01/2021 – 07/2021

USA

Mobile app developer (part-time), Preventa Medical ☑

- Worked on converting an existing web app to a fully functional flutter web app.
- Proposed best practices of flutter and maintaining a clean + clear + simple flutter web app

06/2019 - 12/2019

Trainee Software Enginner, *Mitra Innovations* **☑**

- Contributed to building rapid applications using Flask with Flask app builder and using PostgreSQL database with Pgadmin4.
- Contributed to customizing flask big data visualize platform Apache superset

Certificates

AWS Certified Solution Architect – Associate □

Education

10/2016 – 07/2021 Moratuwa, Sri Lanka **BSc in Computer Science and Engineering,** *University of Moratuwa* ☑

08/2015 – 08/2016 Gampaha, Sri Lanka **Diploma in IT,** ESoft Metro Campus ☑

Skills

Fullstack

Java, Spring Boot, JPA, Maven, Tomcat, Flask, Angular

Cloud / PAAS

AWS, GCP, Firebase

CI/CD

Docker, Kubernetes, Git lab Runner, Fastlane, Codemagic

Mobile

Flutter, Android • iOS • SQLite • Ionic

Database

Oracle, Firestore, MySQL, PosgressSQL

Other

Auth0, Google Maps, Elastic Search, Grafana , Kafka

Projects

03/2022 - present

Flutter Widget Catcher 🗷

- Sometimes copying the flutter widget from the web can be tricky. Because finding correct closing parenthesis might be quite cumbersome. Flutter widget catcher is a useful widget to copy Flutter Widgets
- Technologies: JavaScript

01/2020 - 09/2020

- At that time there was no way to collect payment from Payhere (payhere.lk)
 using Flutter so I decided to create a plugin that would help anyone to collect
 payment using the Payhere payment gateway.
- Technologies: Java, Dart/Flutter

Thel - SL fuel Finder 🗷

- We had a fuel shortage in our country there were long queues near fuel stations. I decided to create this app, this will help people to find fuel availability at filling stations in Sri Lanka.
- · Technologies: Dart/Flutter. GCP, Android

Organizations

2020 - 2021

IEEE Computer Society University of Moratuwa, President

- IEEE xtreme 13.0 campus ambassador
- Oragnizing Mora Xtreme coding competion more than 400 participation